Countries collection, 1540-2006 (bulk 1920-1970)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Great Britain [see England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales]
  - Nyasaland [see Malawi]
    - United States
      - Regions and States
        - Massachusetts
          - "A World Affairs Project of the Massachusetts Federation of Business and Professional Women for the Bicentennial Year, 1975-76, Hampshire County BPW" (Box 57, Folder 9)
        - Michigan
          - "'Courage Was The Fashion' a Chronicle Play of Women's Place in Detroit's History," Detroit's 250th Birthday Festival, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 10-13)
          - Journal of our travel to the west (to Grand Rapids, Michigan) by Elizabeth Bailey Foote: typescript, 1843-44 (Box 57, Folder 14)
        - Minnesota: "Chronicles of a Minnesota Pioneer" by Tilla Regina Dahl Deen, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Montana, The Montana Woman, scattered issues, 1945-53 (Box 58, Folder 2)
        - Nebraska, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - Nevada, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - New Hampshire: "They Paved the Way: A History of N.H. Women," by Olive Tardiff, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 5)
        - New Jersey: "The New Jersey Cavalcade!" radio scripts, New Jersey Writer's Project, 1940 (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
        - New York, 1966, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
        - North Carolina, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
        - North Dakota, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 3)
        - Ohio
          - General, 1892-1964 (Box 59, Folder 4)
          - "Ohio Women," Women's Services Division, Ohio Bureau of Employment Services, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 5)
          - Our Acre and its Harvest, U. S. Sanitary Commission, Cleveland Branch, 1869 (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - Oregon: "Our Journey Across the Plains from Missouri to Oregon" by A. A. (Mrs. D. J.) Cooper: typescript, 1931 (Box 59, Folder 7)
        - Pennsylvania "Report of the State's Commission on Women's Work," World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 59, Folder 8)
        - South Carolina, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
        - Tennessee, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 10)
        - Texas, 1898-1978 (Box 59, Folder 11)
        - Vermont, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Uruguay
      - Biographical materials, 1930-63, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Clippings, 1940-57 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - General, 1919-54, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Women's Organizations
        - Asociacion Cristiana Feminina (YWCA), 1952 (Box 59, Folder 13)
        - Consejo Nacional de Mujeres del Uruguay, 1919 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Venezuela
      - Biographical materials
        - General, 1928, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - Elisa Elvira Zuloaga, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1940-71 (Box 48, Folder 3-8)
      - General, 1944-77, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Vietnam
      - Clippings1957-71 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - General, 1948-77, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Women's Organizations
        - General, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - The Vietnamese Women Association, 1965, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Vietnamese Women's Association for Service to Soceity, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Wales, 1891-1924, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Yemen, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Yugoslavia
      - Clippings, 1925-30 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - General, 1943-61 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Publications
        - Faits et Tendances 4 1968-69 (Box 49, Folder 10)
        - Women of Yugoslavia by Olga Kovačić, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 11)
        - Women's Rights in Yugoslavia, 1961 (Box 49, Folder 12)
        - ena danas, May 1950 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - "Reader: Women's Initiatives, Zagreb, Ljubljana, Belgrad" by Rosa Logar and Barbara Schiestl, during war, circa 1994 (Box 49, Folder 14-18)
      - Women's Organizations: Council of Associations for Child Welfare and Federation of Women's Societies of Yugoslavia, 1961-62 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Zambia, 1963-64 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Zanzibar, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Zimbabwe [see also Rhodesia]
      - Clippings, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 22)
      - General, 1979, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - World Regions
      - Africa
        - General, 1925-68, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
        - Clippings, 1925-77 (Box 60, Folder 3)
        - African Training and Research Centre for Women (ATRCW): bibliography, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 4)
        - "African Women Speak," Regional Seminar of World Union of Catholic Women's Organizations, Lomé, Togo, Jul 1958 (Box 60, Folder 5)
        - "Christian Women in Africa Share In Responsibility," Apr 1963 (Box 60, Folder 6)
        - Conference of Women of Africa and African Descent, Accra, Ghana, Jul 1960 (Box 60, Folder 7)
        - "Consultations in Africa," World Council of Churches, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 8)
        - Council of West African Women, 1960-61 (Box 60, Folder 9)
        - Report of the Seminar 'The African Woman Designs Her Future,' Ibadan, Nigeria, Aug 1960 (Box 60, Folder 10)
        - Report on the Seminar, "The Challenge of Women's New Status in Modern Africa," International Alliance of Women, Monrovia, Liberia, Jul-Aug 1963 (Box 60, Folder 11)
        - United Nations Economic Commission for Africa, Workshop on Urban Problems: The Role of Women in Economic Development, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 12)
        - United Nations Seminar on Participation of Women in Public Life, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1960-61 (Box 60, Folder 13)
        - WIN News reports on female genital mutilation, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 14)
        - World YWCA All-Africa Conference, Jan 1961 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - First Asian-African Conference of Women, Colombo, Ceylon, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      - First Conference of Afro-Asian Women, Cairo, Egypt, 1961 (Box 60, Folder 17)
      - Asia
        - General, 1912-59 (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - Clippings, 1929-79 (Box 61, Folder 2)
        - All-Asian Women's Conference, Lahore, Jan 1931
          - General, 1929-31 (Box 61, Folder 3)
          - Proceedings, 1931 (Box 61, Folder 4)
        - East Asian Textile Women Leaders Conference, Textile Workers' Asian Regional Organization (TWARO), Nagoya, Japan, Oct 1970 (Box 61, Folder 5)
        - Federation of Asian Women's Associations, 1959, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 6)
        - "Reality and Vision: A Report of the First Asian Seminar on Mental Health and Family Life," Baguio, Philippines, Dec 1958 (Box 61, Folder 7)
        - "Report to the Governments of Ceylon, India, Indonesia, Japan, Pakistan, the Philippines and Thailand on Conditions of Women's Work in Seven Asian Countries," International Labour Office, 1958 (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Asia-Pacific: Fourth Regional Conference of Pacific Women: Report, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Central America, 1966-67 (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - Europe, 1974-76 (Box 61, Folder 11)
      - Latin America
        - General, 1913-75, undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
        - Clippings, 1920-63 (Box 61, Folder 13-14)
        - Conferencia de las Mujeres de Negocios y Profesionales de las Americas, Nov 1961 (Box 61, Folder 15)
        - Ideas: Revista de las Mujeres de America, Ano III, Nos. 35-36Jun-Jul 1947 (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Latin American Perspectives, special issue: Population and Imperialism and Women in Revolution, fall 1977 (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - "Prominent Women of Latin America" by Kathleen Tappen and Bernice T. Morris, Research Division, Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, Jul 1944 (Box 62, Folder 3)
        - Second Latin American Regional Seminar for Women Volunteers in National Development, Santiago, Chile, Jun-Jul 1965 (Box 62, Folder 4)
        - United Nations Economic and Social Council (UNESCO) reports, 1965, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Middle East and North Africa
        - General, 1924-75 (Box 62, Folder 6)
        - Clippings, 1961-75, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - Neapolitan Captive, by Viletta Laranda, 1830 [FRAGILE-may not be photocopied] (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - "Rapport sur la Traite des Femmes et des Enfants dans les Territoires du Levant sous Mandat Français," 1930 (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - Reports by Nabia Abbott, American Journal of Semitic Languages and Literatures, 1941-42 (Box 62, Folder 10)
        - Women, by Habib Effendi al-Zayyat al-Dimashqi 1898-99 (in Arabic) [FRAGILE-may not be photocopied] (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - Women and Economic Development in the Arab World: A Regional Conference, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Native Americans
        - General, 1950, undated (Box 62, Folder 13)
        - Clippings, 1933-71 (Box 62, Folder 14)
        - America Indigena, Vol. VIII, No. 3 Jul 1948 (Box 62, Folder 15)
        - "Handbook of Indian Dances, I. New Mexico Pueblos," Dorothy N. Stewart, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 16)
        - "Indians at Work: A News Sheet for Indians and the Indian Service," Office of Indian Affairs, 1 Dec 1935 (Box 62, Folder 17)
        - Phebe Jewell Nichols (Mrs. Angus F. Lookaround), 1952-57, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - Photographs by F. A. Rinehart, taken at the Indian Congress in Omaha, Nebraska, 1898 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Scandinavia: Scandinavian Review: Women in Public, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - West Indies, 1958-76 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Women in Developing Countries
        - General, 1974-82 (Box 63, Folder 5)
        - "Message From the Village" by Perdita Huston, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 6)
        - "Women's Role in the Development of Tropical and Sub-Tropical Countries," Report of the XXXIth Meeting, International Institute of Differing Civilizations, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Materials
      - Canada: En Lutte!: Supplement pour la journée international des femmes, 24 Feb-3Mar 1981 (Box 64)
      - France: Women's Organizations: Union Féminine Civique et Sociale, La Femme dans la vie Sociale, miscellaneous issues, 1957-68 (Box 64)
      - India: John O'London's Weekly, 24 Jan 1947 (Box 64)
      - Iran: Women & Struggle in Iran, Mar 1982 (Box 64)
      - Mexico: Mujer Cetemista, Nos. 1-2Jan-Feb 1963; Brecha: un periodico realizado por mujeres, 16 Jun 1963 (Box 64)
      - Nicaragua: Tribuna del Magisterio, Jul 1967, Sep 1967 (Box 64)
      - Paraguay: El Feminista, 15 Nov 1963 (Box 64)
      - Peru: Caretas, 17-27 Sep 1963 (Box 64)
      - Philippines: Ewha Voice, Ewha Women's University, 1967; Mr. & Ms., 17 Jan 1978 (Box 64)
      - Poland: clipping showing Mdlle. Postowoytow, 1863; La Femme Polonaise, No. 6 Nov-Dec 1931 (Box 64)
      - Spain: Seccion Femenina de F.E.T.y de las J.O.N.S. Sintesis de su organización, undated (Box 64)
      - Thailand: Standard: A Weekly Newspaper for International Readers, 24 Dec 1960 (Box 64)
      - Turkey: "Turkish Women of To-day" by Ira Nelson Morris, Pictorial Review, Nov 1923; L'Illustration de Turquie, No. 31-32, 1 May 1935; Gençlik Kadinlar Semineri, 1961 (Box 64)
      - USSR" "The Soviet Attack on Women's Minds" by Mary C. Lyne and Dorothy Tuttle, preprinted from August 1953 McCall's; "The Ten Most Influential Women in Russia," Ladies' Home Journal, Apr 1959 (Box 64)
      - United States
        - World War II: "Are Women Doing Their Share in the War?" Saturday Evening Post, 29 Apr 1944 (Box 64)
        - States
          - Massachusetts: "Women" supplement to the Daily Hampshire Gazette, 15 Apr 1982 (Box 64)
        - Regions
          - New England: New England Freedman's Aid Society financial record, 1866-67 (Box 64)
          - South: Southern Struggle, Vol. 39, No. 3Mar 1981 (Box 64)
      - World Regions
        - Asia: "Progress of Asian Women" The Fookien Times, 1959 (Box 64)
        - Middle East and North Africa: "The Arab Woman: An Untypical View," Aramco World Magazine, Mar-Apr 1971 (Box 64)
      - Canada: poster celebrating 1 year anniversary of Bill 18, 1941 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Congo: Poster for Radio Congo Belge "Le Cours to Français…nous ecouton chaque jour aux emission africaines de Radio Congo Belge," undated (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - England: "Her Majesty's Glorious Jubilee," 1891 {missing?} (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - France: marriage certificates1540, 1549; Anarchist Federation poster; La Vie Française 20 Jun 1919 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Italy: "Noi siamo donne ma cambieremo," L'Espresso26 Mar 1972; Il Manifesto, 5 Nov 1972; 3, 10, 13, & 18 Feb 1973; 18 & 27 Mar 1973; 1 Apr 1973; 24 May 1973; 28 Jun 1973; 5 Jul 1973 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Japan: posters for "Women's Week" (gift of Mary Ritter Beard)circa 1922; Womens' and Minors' Bureau Women's Week poster, n.d. (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Pakistan: MAG Weekly; 23 Aug 1984 All Pakistan Women's Association: posters (2)., undated (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Puerto Rico: Gomez, Maria Lebertad: campaign poster, undated (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Saint Lucia: Issue of Voice of St. Lucia celebrating the 10th Anniversary of the St. Lucia Women's Association, 7 Sep 1963 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Sweden: Tidevarvet, Liberal Women's Federation, 1 Jun 1929 FRAGILE (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - Switzerland: Schweizer Frauenblatt, 2 Feb 1962 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - United States, California: Olive A. Oatman - Broadside: Lecture on her captivity, 1859 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)
      - World Regions: The Exchange Report: Women in the Third World, circa 1980 (Map-case flat file drawer 1)